Enda Phelan

Address Geevagh, Co. Sligo
Phone +353 (0)86 8711307
Email hello@endaphelan.me

Website <u>endaphelan.me</u>

LinkedIn <u>ie.linkedin.com/in/endaphelan</u>
GitHub <u>github.com/craicoverflow</u>

I am an open-minded, intelligent and enthusiastic software developer with a passion for everything technology related. Through self-interest I am always aware of the latest industry and technological developments. I love to code (both at work and at home), listen to technology podcasts and read articles online.

I take pride in my programming ability. I set myself a high standard and consistently achieved high grades in university, receiving the award for the highest overall grade in my year with a GPA of 74%. I have 2 years' experience as a professional software engineer, working mostly with JavaScript, PHP or C# complimented with a number of other technologies.

Skills

 $\label{eq:charge_continuous_con$

Education

BSc (Hons) in Computing in Software Development - Institute of Technology, Sligo. 2015-2016.

Focus: Advanced software development concepts and techniques, including artificial intelligence (67%), advanced .NET programming (93%), mobile development (78%) and human computer interaction (67%). **Final Grade:** 1.1

BSc in Computing in Software Development - Institute of Technology, Sligo. 2012-2015.

Focus: Object-oriented programming, primarily on the .NET platform with C#. Course content included database development, software project management, software quality testing and web programming. In third year there was a group project and a three-month industry work placement.

Final Grade: 2.1

Experience

Software Engineer - Qpercom, Galway. *June 2016-December 2017*. **Key technologies:** PHP (5.6 + 7.1), Eloquent ORM, Angular 1 & 2, A, Slim Framework, MySQL, Docker, Rackspace, Vim, PHPStorm, Visual Studio Code, Git, Gulp, Bash.

- Upgraded the company's REST API from Slim Framework 2.x to 3.x and overhauled its design and architecture due to serious performance issues, implementing features such as autowired dependency injection and the repository pattern.
- Involved in research and development of a new product being developed in the company.
- Creating user stories based on a specification document and through collaboration with the company's CEO.
- Performing extensive research (technical and non-technical) to break down user stories into defined tasks which I add to our issue tracking system JIRA and separate into sprints.
- Implementing a task by building upon the codebase of the client application and REST API, and making changes to the database structure if necessary.
- Once a task is complete, I test the new feature thoroughly.
- Deploying applications to the Rackspace cloud platform.
- Writing and maintaining internal documentation using apiDoc and Markdown.
- On-site support for OSCE examinations running our software, my main tasks being setting up the exam stations with laptops/tablets and training examiners in how to use the system.
- Communicating with university staff in the weeks before an exam in which we are doing on-site support to gather requirements such as examiner lists, equipment required.

Providing friendly customer support via telephone, email and Pubble (live-chat).

Software Development Intern - Vulcan Solutions, Galway. *April 2015-September 2015*. **Key technologies:** C#, ASP.NET (Web Forms/MVC), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, VBA, Microsoft Dynamics CRM, Adxstudio, Visual Studio 2015.

Vulcan Solutions (now Codec-dss) were a provider of customer relationship management systems (CRM) to the higher education and government sectors of Ireland.

- Filled the role of QA for a few weeks, thoroughly testing applications to find any bugs and to ensure that the specified user stories could be completed. Ranking issues by severity and adding them to the issue tracker with a description of the problem.
- Fully involved in an agile team of 4 developers, contributing C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery to
 web applications for clients in higher education, including Dublin City University, University College
 Cork and National College of Ireland.
- Creating entities, forms and rules in Microsoft Dynamics CRM client solutions.
- Developing custom plugins in C# for Microsoft Dynamics CRM client solutions to extend the functionality of CRM forms.
- Full responsibility to develop the user interface for the DCU student portal, liaising with members of DCU staff to ensure that the branding requirements were met and that the design fulfilled their vision.
- Involved in sprint planning meetings to help define the work and effort necessary to complete the product backlog for the upcoming sprint.
- Automated the process of turning monthly support ticket data into meaningful tables and charts in Microsoft Excel, using VBA macros.
- Involved in upgrading National College of Ireland's student portal, which uses the Adxstudio Portals technology, from version 6.x to version 7.x.
- Completed the final week of a scrum sprint on my own when the other members of my team were absent for various reasons.
- Deploying the latest client applications to the Azure platform.

Volunteering

English Teacher - Homestay Saigon, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. July 2018 (3 weeks).

I volunteered to teach English for 3 weeks while travelling in Vietnam. I saw this as an opportunity to learn more about the Vietnamese culture and improve my communication and organisation skills. *Typical duties*:

- Lesson preparation.
- Teaching English to classes of 4-8 students.
- One-to-one private classes with advanced students.
- Cooking and cleaning.

Mentor - CoderDojo, Bank of Ireland, Sligo. September 2015-May 2016.

I became a mentor at a local CoderDojo group as I wanted to give something back to the community and help start the careers of future programmers. My main responsibilities included:

- Teaching students between the ages of 10 and 16 to code by helping with Scratch, HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- Providing advice to students who had questions about programming or technology in general.
- As the only mentor with any programming experience I helped to devise the course content and structure.

Interests

 $\label{eq:programming} \begin{array}{l} \textbf{Programming} \cdot \textbf{Linux} \cdot \textbf{football} \cdot \textbf{running} \cdot \textbf{music} \cdot \textbf{reading} \cdot \textbf{travelling} \cdot \textbf{hiking} \cdot \textbf{podcasts} \cdot \textbf{photography} \cdot \textbf{videography} \cdot \textbf{blogging} \cdot \textbf{video} \ \textbf{editing/production} \\ \end{array}$

References

Available upon request